TRISTAN SLATER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

\$\ +1 778 922 3004□ hello@trslater.ca

O trslater

in tristanslater

I am a software engineering graduate from the University of Victoria with more than 12 years of experience in the tech industry, working on projects for large companies such as Coca-Cola and eBay, teaching technology classes at the University of Alberta, and running my own freelance web development business.

EDUCATION

Sep 2016–Apr 2023 Victoria BC

Bachelor of Software Engineering (BSEng)

University of Vectoria

- Cumulative GPA: 7.65 (~3.8)
 - ML specialization
 - o Graphics specialization

EXPERIENCE

Sep 2019-Dec 2020 Victoria BC

Front End Developer (Co-Op)

SunTracker Technologies Inc.

- Headed rebuild of greenhouse designer web app GUI
 - o Headed rebuild of greenhouse designer app server in Python Django
 - o Developed, deployed, and managed an NGINX web server
 - Developed a Python interface for proprietary C++ library

Sep 2018-Aug 2019 Victoria BC

Software Developer (Co-Op)

Viral Bioinformatics Resource Center, Department of Biochemistry & Microbiology, University of Victoria

- o Developed, deployed, and maintained Java-based bioinformatics tools
- o Initiated several security and workflow improvements
- Headed rebuild of EC2 instance after attack
- Managed AWS EC2 instances
- o Initiated, defined requirements for ReactJS-based pilot project
- o Maintained WordPress website

Oct 2011-Sep 2013 Edmonton AB

Contract Instructor

University of Alberta's Technology Training Centre

- Developed and taught courses in web development
- o Taught cources in Microsoft Office and Creative Suite
- o Consistently received excellent feedback from students

May 2008—Sep 2016 Edmonton AB / Victoria BC

Freelance Web Developer

Self Employed

- o Created websites for a wide variety of clients from realtors to storytellers
- Managed client project life-cycle from conception to maintenance
- o Constantly developed and improved development process/toolchain
- Learned PHP, JavaScript, and MySQL to create custom interactive content
- Kept ended with relevant web technologies, frameworks, such as HTML5/CSS3 and WordPress

Aug 2004-Mar 2008 West Kelowna BC

Java

Creative Designer

PureSafety Inc. (now part of UL)

- Embraced chance for learning and development
- Learned ActionScript to contribute to interactive learning activities
- Used scripts to automate production
- Worked with big names such as Coca-Cola and eBay

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Languages	Libraries	Dev Tools	UNIX
Python	• FastAPI	Git/GitHub	 Filesystem
 JavaScript 	Django	 Docker 	 CLI tools
HTML/CSS	∘ MkDocs	• AWS	• Bash
o C/C++	React	 Visual Studio Code 	